I call the phenomenon "Revival."
I go back in time by about one to five minutes
and watch the same scene play out again.
It's always right before something bad happens.
As a result, I've prevented
several accidents from occurring.
Welcome back, Satoru.
Ma.
Are you Fujinuma Satoru-san?
I need to take you down to the station.
Did you watch Maskman?
Next week's the last episode.
I forgot to watch Black!
1988...
February the 15th?
Good morning, everyone.
Good morning!
What's wrong, Satoru? Take your seat already.
Huh? Oh, r-right...
Where was my seat, again?
Are you half-asleep, Fujinuma?
That's Hinazuki's desk.
Monday...
Kayo's late again this week, huh?
Do you like Kayo, Fujinuma?
You two weirdos would make a perfect couple.
I'm taking attendance.
Is this real life?
Azuma.
Here!
Abiko.
Why did I end up here?
Abe.
Here!
Ikuta.
What is going on?
Here!
We're talking about 18 years ago here!
How far did you get in Dragon Quest III?
I'm level 15 now.
That's all?!
Just kidding. I'm actually level 25.
Yeah, right!
What's up, Satoru?
My head kinda hurts.
I'm going to the nurse's office.
With your bag?
Whatever.
I'll let the teacher know.
What the hell is going on?
Is this a Revival?
But why like this?
It makes no sense.
Ma!
H-Hello.
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Oh, just some stranger.
Oh, right.
She would be at work.
Ma...
I'm back.
Ma.
"Ma"?
What? I said "Mom."
You silly goose.
Do you want Hamburg steak
or meatballs for dinner?
H-Hamburg steak.
I'll be done soon.
Just this morning, you threw a tantrum
'cause your recorder was missing,
but I guess you're over it already.
I'm sorry, Mom.
You don't have to have a cry about it.
I had times like these, too, huh?
Had I forgotten about them?
No, I just hadn't realized.
Times I'd never given a second thought to...
And times I'd lost forever.
This is definitely a Revival.
A second chance.
I won't ever let go of these times again.
Mom.
That was great. Thank you.
What's gotten into you, Satoru?
Thanks for the food!
My pleasure.
Am I going to relive 18 years of my life like this?
Morning, Satoru.
H-Hey, Osamu.
If this actually is a Revival,
I must be here for a reason.
It must be to prevent
something bad from happening.
In other words, is this where
I have to start to save Ma?
But why here?
I haven't noticed anything wrong.
Hinazuki Kayo.
She lived with her mother,
if my memory serves me right.
That's awesome.
It's perfect.
A bruise?
This group really is weird.
I can't talk about Dragon Quest with any of you.
Y-Yeah...
I mean, Hiro's more into Final Fantasy,
and Kazu only plays shooters.
Hiro...
Kazu...
I'm starting to remember.
And Satoru doesn't even have a Nintendo!
Was that so?
But, Osamu, you can't talk to fellow Dragon Quest
fans about anything but Dragon Quest, right?
I like this group because
we're all into different things.
Kenya.
He's a smart guy,
just like I thought he was back then.
By the way, Satoru...
Mind if I ask you something?
What is it?
Do you like Hinazuki?
You were staring at her the whole time in class.
Really?!
Come to think of it, he stopped and
stared at Hinazuki this morning, too.
What's this, Satoru?
Why didn't you talk to us about it?
Leave it to me!
Wha—
I'll set you up with Hinazuki!
K-Keep it down!
U-Uh, I wouldn't say that I like her,
but she's been on my mind a bit.
He said it!
Satoru-kun, you've got guts!
Well said, my boy!
I'll get you to meet with her after school!
Are you stupid?
Not pulling any punches, huh?
That's the first thing you've got to say?
I said that out loud.
Damn that Kazu.
He went and told her straight up that I like her.
L-Look...
I thought maybe we could be friends.
We go home the same way, after all.
What about me gave you that idea?
This brat is a pain in the ass.
But I kinda get it.
Because, Fujinuma,
you're a fake, just like me.
What's with her?
What is she saying?
I saw you running back home yesterday.
Is your mother that important to you?
Yeah.
Oh.
W-Wait, Hinazuki!
I wanna be friends with you!
You wanna be my friend?
Then...
Could you kill someone for me?
I could've saved her!
Hinazuki was in a bad situation even before she was murdered.
If I can right this wrong, then maybe...
Because, Fujinuma,
you're a fake, just like me.
It's not like she realized I'm posing as my past self.
While it's true that I was
winging my way through life,
I was the same back in elementary school, too.
I was playing the role of my ideal self
so I could get along with people.
Don't be embarrassed. Show some courage.
It was all so I could fit into this cramped society.
Sorry about that.
Were you taking a dump in there?
No!
Took you long enough.
She must've seen through that.
I thought you'd fell in!
Probably clogged the thing.
She said "just like me,"
which means she's probably the same.
You've got the hots for her, huh, Satoru?
Speaking of which, how'd it go with Hinazuki?
Did you manage to ask her to walk home together?
N-Nah, we just chatted a bit.
You chatted? Alone?
Yeah.
That means you've got a chance!
No way she'd talk to you alone otherwise!
Is there anything else you want me to tell her for you?
How irritating.
This is so exciting!
How am I supposed to deal with these morons?
Quit fooling around, you guys.
What if you rush it and ruin things for him?
Good point.
He's still way off, but I appreciate it.
Satoru.
We'll all still be in the same class
in sixth grade, so take it slow and steady.
Got it.
School will be closing shortly.
Come to think of it, when did Hinazuki disappear?
Time could be running out.
Let's go, Satoru.
C-Coming.
Huh?
Don't you have a new pair of McGregor gloves?
Oh yeah, I did have those.
I think I left them somewhere.
Probably at the hideout.
You guys wanna stop by the hideout?
What are you talking about?
We decided we wouldn't go right after
snowfall because we'd leave footprints.
I-Is that so?
See you tomorrow!
Laters!
Kenya!
Thanks for earlier.
Honestly, it bugs me when people
make a big deal out of things.
No kidding.
Well, don't worry about it.
Hey, Satoru...
I don't know why, but I get this feeling that
Hinazuki being on your mind
is something really important.
This might not be any of my business,
but you can talk to us if you need anything.
I'm sure all of us want to help you out.
Sure. Thanks.
I get that they don't mean any harm.
It was thanks to Kazu that
I got to talk to Hinazuki, anyway.
So, how'd it really go?
With Hinazuki.
Did you get to talk to her?
Yeah.
I think she spoke to me from the heart a little.
That so?
By the way, Satoru.
Lately, have you...
read the student anthology?
N-No, I haven't.
It's actually pretty interesting.
Go through it sometime.
Laters. See you tomorrow.
Laters.
Kenya was probably referring to Hinazuki's essay.
"The Town With Only Me Erased," by Hinazuki Kayo.
When I grow older, old enough
to go wherever I want by myself,
I want to go to a faraway country.
I want to go to a faraway island.
I want to go to an island with nobody around.
I want to go to an island
with no sorrow or suffering.
An island without adults, children,
classmates, teachers, or Mom.
On that island, I'll climb a tree when I want,
swim in the ocean when I want,
and sleep when I want.
And on that island, I'll think about the town
from which only I've been erased.
Kids will go to school as always,
adults will go to work as always,
and Mom will have dinner as always.
When I think about the town from which
I've been erased, I feel lighthearted.
I want to go far, far away.
Hinazuki's essay is most definitely an SOS.
I'm home!
Let's eat.
Kenya probably thinks
I took an interest in Hinazuki
not because I have a crush on her,
but because I read her essay.
Mom.
What?
On my birthday, can I invite
some friends over and have a party?
Y-Yeah, sure.
But we can't fit too many in this tiny apartment.
Don't worry. Only need room for about five.
This is the first time you've
ever asked for anything like this.
Wanna get a big cake?
Yeah. Thanks.
What I'm supposed to do now
is dig deep and get closer to Hinazuki.
I'll do things I never did in the past,
change Hinazuki's actions that way,
and prevent all the incidents
that occur around me in the future.
If I keep that up...
Satoru, you awake?
Five people?
Did you get a girlfriend?
What, you're asleep?
She's a demon.
That reminds me.
I never showed Mom my essay because
I couldn't stand the gaze of her all-seeing eye.
What did I write about, again?
All right, time to go home and play Dragon Quest!
Me too!
It's snowing again?
We can't go to the hideout.
Satoru, Hinazuki's leaving.
Shouldn't you go after her?
Osamu.
It's fine, Kenya. I will go after her.
Thanks, Osamu.
Laters!
Satoru-kun's got guts!
No need to run.
I know just where to find Hinazuki.
I suspect she's being abused by her mother,
which is why she doesn't want to go home
and loiters at that park until it gets dark.
And I just thought she was a weird girl.
Hinazuki.
Fujinuma?
What're you doing here?
Right back at you.
I said I wanna be friends with you, remember?
I can't murder anyone for you, though.
I was obviously kidding.
Yikes. I have trouble with these types.
You're, like, putting on an act, aren't you?
Pretending to smile.
Pretending to be nice.
Pretending to be worried.
I don't think that's a bad thing.
Not that I'm one to talk,
but I can't see the real you.
You're probably right.
I am putting on an act.
I want people to like me.
I want friends.
I'm bad with people, so I thought about
what I could do to achieve that.
And I figured I could try liking everyone.
When I did, putting on that act got a little easier.
Yeah, I feel like if you play a part,
it'll eventually become a part of you.
I feel like if you say something
out loud, it'll eventually come true.
It's just like what Airi said,
which made me feel nostalgic.
In order to get what they want,
everyone puts up with things,
makes an effort, and picks up skills.
When they fall, they pick themselves back up.
Hinazuki must be the same.
I bet she's bearing something right now.
Unlike me, she's putting on a stoic act.
She acts as if she feels nothing.
But there's no way a girl who's only
ten years old could be that strong.
Hinazuki.
Take this.
I'm throwing a birthday party.
You should come.
A-Are you sure you want me to?
A lot of other people will be there, right?
I don't know yet.
I decided to ask you first.
It's on March 2nd.
You'll come, right?
S-Sure.
Fujinuma, aren't your hands cold?
W-Well, they are...
Looks like I left my gloves somewhere.
Hey. You're 29 years old. Get a hold of yourself.
What are you blushing for?
Fujinuma, I'm done.
My hand's a little bigger than yours, huh?
Are you stupid?
But you know what?
You're kinda easy to talk to lately.
Well...
I did decide not to lie to you.
I said that out loud.
H-Hinazuki!
Laters!
See you tomorrow!
She wasn't wearing gloves either.
This is where I last saw Hinazuki 18 years ago.
I think her body was only
found after the snow melted.
I won't let Hinazuki be alone in this park.
I...
I want to change the future!